# Karan.guptage

#### **PROFILE**

Senior Full Stack Developer who has possessed various web backend & frontend languages/frameworks and blockchain technology with over 7 years of experience in requirements gathering, analysis, design, implementation, maintenance of software applications and testing Client/Server and Web applications.

Demonstrated ability to satisfy upper management through reliability, commitment, and problem resolution.

## **Experience**

- Front end Engineer (Remote) 09/2012 - 04/2016

Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and

speed. Collaborate with senior level usability specialists and technology/business leaders to interpret requirements into interactive experiences. Conduct research and developed creative processes by sharing new trends and development technologies with other designers.

back end Developer (Remote) 05/2016 - 11/2022
 Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high

traffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase

in sales revenue. Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for various projects.

Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement, that minimized downtime by 13%.

### - Full stack Developer (Remote) 12/2022 - 09/2024

Developed and launched a robust website using MERN Stack and TypeScript, demonstrating proficiency in full-stack development.

Built proprietary nodes on both Ethereum and Binance blockchain networks for effective data analysis, demonstrating deep understanding of blockchain technology.

Successfully deployed the website on Amazon Web Services (AWS), showcasing competency in cloud platforms and deployment protocols.

Lead the development team in establishing an infrastructure that enables realtime data retrieval from proprietary nodes, showcasing leadership skills and understanding of real-time data processing.

## **Education** 04/2008 - 08/2012

Bachelor's degree - Information Technology, Alberta University

## **Skills**

```
React,
Next,
JavaScript/TypeScript,
PHP,
CodeIgnither,
Laravel,
Python,
Django,
Vue,
Web3.js,
Node.js,
NoSQL/MongoDB,
MySQL/PostgreSQL,
```